A Guide to the State Fair of Virginia Records, 1927-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
State Fair of Virginia Records, 1927-2005
The Library of Virginia
42808
27 cubic feet
State Fair of Virginia, Inc.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the State Fair of Virginia, Inc., Mechanicsville, Virginia 23111
Historical Information
In 1854, the Virginia State Agricultural Society was formed, and its first organized exhibition was held that year. In 1906, the State Fair was held on the grounds of what would later become The Diamond baseball field, home of the Richmond Braves. In 1946, the Virginia State Fair became known as the Atlantic Rural Exposition, and it location was again moved. The State Fair of Virginia, Inc. is a not-for-profit 501(c)(3) organization. Its mission is to celebrate Virginia's heritage - to heed its roots in agriculture, advance its youth through scholarships, encourage friendly competition and foster multicultural celebrations in a fun, safe atmosphere.
Scope and Content
Records, 1927-2005, of the State Fair of Virginia, including newspaper clippings, news releases, photographs and slides, posters, drawings, brochures, scrapbooks, plaques, and ephemera.
Contents List
- Clippings and News Releases, 1968-1969. (Box 1)
- Clipping (framed, not boxed), 1973.
- Clippings and News Releases, 1974. (Box 2)
- Clippings and News Releases, 1975. (Box 3)
- Clippings, 1976. (Box 4)
- Clippings, 1995. (Box 5)
- Clippings, 1996. (Box 6)
- Clippings, 1997-1998. (Box 7)
- Plaques (Fair Prizes) (Box 8)
- Ribbons, Stickers, Certificates, Tri-Corner Colonial Hat, Ephemera (Box 9)
- Central Virginia Regional Fair by the James (35mm Slides), Regional Fairs - Guidelines and Procedures, 1997 (Box 10)
- Film - State Fair, 1956 (28:49) (Box 11)
- Photographs (Box 12-13)
- Poster - Strawberry Hill Races (Framed), 1985. (Box 14)
- Poster - State Fair of Virginia (Framed), 1997. (Box 14)
- Poster - Henrico Education Foundation Inc. "Children Are Our Business (Box 14)
- Brochure Mock-Up - 1984 State Fair (Two Panels) (Box 15)
- Brochures (Box 15)
- Flyer Mock-Up - 1982 State Fair (Box 15)
- Program Mock-Up, n.d. (Box 15)
- Poster - Octoberfest (Box 15)
- Poster - Octoberfest (Box 15)
- Poster Mock-Up - Margo "The Tennessee Yodeler" (Box 15)
- Posters - State Fair of Virginia, n.d. (Three Copies) (Box 15)
- Poster - Hell Drivers (Two Copies) (Box 15)
- Poster - Thrill Show (Box 15)
- Poster - Featuring Conklin's Magic Midway (Box 15)
- Poster - Success on Ice (Box 15)
- Poster - 61's Festival of Fun (Confederate) (Box 15)
- Mounted Poster - State Fair "Salute to America, 1984" (Box 15)
- State Fair Park Sign (Box 15)
- State Fair Park Community Meeting Directional Sign (Box 15)
- Map Showing Location of State Fairgrounds (Box 15)
- Large Folder Containing 1988 Materials (brochure and poster mock-ups, slides, photos, and promotional literature) (Box 15)
- Drawing - American Heritage Village (Box 16)
- Drawing - Old Time General Store (Box 16)
- Drawing - Pioneer Farmstead (Box 16)
- Mounted Drawing (For Poster?) (Box 16)
- Mounted Drawing, 1984 (For Poster?) (Box 16)
- Mounted Photographs (For Poster?), 1984. (Box 17)
- Mounted Photographs - Oxen in Heritage Village, 1992. (Box 17)
- Mounted Photographs - Heritage Village, 1993. (Box 17)
- Mounted Photographs - State Fair (Four Panels), 1995. (Box 17)
- Mounted Photographs - "Party with the Animals", 1995. (Box 17)
- Mounted Photographs (For Poster?), 2005. (Box 17)
- Mounted Photographs of Previous State Fairs (Box 17)
- Mounted Photographs (Framed) - Heritage Village (not boxes)
- Framed Aerial Photograph of State Fair, 1980. (Box 18)
- Framed Photographs - American Heritage Village, 1990. (Box 18)
- Framed Photographs - American Heritage Village, 1992. (Box 18)
- Framed Photographs - Pioneer Farmstead Reproduction (Box 18)
- Framed Photographs - American Heritage Showcase (Box 18)
- B & W Photograph of Girl Watching Horse (Box 18)
- Aerial Photographs of State Fair (Box 19)
- B & W Photograph of Wooden Structure (Framed and Unframed) (Box 19)
- B & W Photographs of Couple in Period Costume (Box 19)
- Organization Chart (Framed), 1965. (Box 19)
- Scrapbook, 1927. (Box 20)
- Scrapbook, 1945-1947. (Box 20)
- Scrapbook, 1947-1948. (Box 20)
- Scrapbook, 1952. (Box 21)
- Scrapbook, 1954. (Box 21)
- Scrapbook, 1956. (Box 21)
- Scrapbook, 1957. (Box 22)
- Scrapbook, 1958. (Box 22)
- Scrapbook, 1960. (Box 22)
- Scrapbook, 1961. (Box 23)
- Scrapbook, 1962-1964. (Box 23)
- Scrapbook, 1965. (Box 24)
- Scrapbook, 1966. (Box 24)
- Scrapbook, 1967. (Box 25)
- Scrapbook, 1968 (Two Volumes). (Box 25)
- Scrapbook, 1969. (Box 26)
- Scrapbook, 1970 (Two Volumes). (Box 26)
- Scrapbook, 1971. (Box 27)
- Scrapbook, 1972. (Box 27)
- Scrapbook, 1980. (Box 28)
- Scrapbook, 1981. (Box 28)
- Scrapbook, 1982. (Box 28)
- Scrapbook, 1983. (Box 29)
- Scrapbook, 1984. (Box 29)
- Scrapbook, 1985. (Box 29)
- Scrapbook, 1986. (Box 30)
- Scrapbook, 1987. (Box 30)
- Scrapbook, 1988. (Box 30)
- Scrapbook, 1989. (Box 31)
- Scrapbook, 1990. (Box 31)
- Scrapbook, 1991. (Box 32)
- Scrapbook, 1992. (Box 32)